Contact

+962792938980 (Mobile) yazansharawi25@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/yazansharawi (LinkedIn) sharawi.me/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Generative Al
User Experience Design (UED)
Full-Stack Development

Languages

English (Full Professional)
German (Elementary)
Arabic (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Fundamentals Google UI/UX Design The complete 2021 flutter development bootcamp with dart IEEE Xtreme Data analysis Track(MileStone 2)

Honors-Awards

First place award in core values
First place overall
First place project

Yazan Sharawi

GenAl @ PwC | Software Engineer | Google Certified UX design, Data analytics, Cybersecurity

Amman, Jordan

Summary

Growing up, I was that annoying little boy who asked questions about everything and wanted to know how everything worked and I am still that annoying boy, but a curious one. I used to be shy and preferred not to talk to anyone, but that all changed when I joined my school's robotics team, which opened up a whole new world for me.

At this point in my life, I had met amazing new people, traveled the world, and above all, learned from a young age how to face challenges and work as a team to solve them, and I had become familiar with coding and using the problem-solving method to help us succeed, and all of that success was because of my family who showed me their support and love, and for my teacher who gave me his time and effort, and it was here that I learned that giving back to people is a great thing.

Enrolling in a computer science program at the university had been my goal since high school; I knew it would be a new and different experience, but I also knew one thing: I needed to find a mentor who is more experienced than me and can lead me to be better, and thank God, I found my mentor who guided me and is still guiding me through the university, and he helped me strengthen my skills by participating in many coding competitions and meeting new people, and he also shares my passion for helping others.

By following him, I was able to develop many skills such as problemsolving and coding with C++, C, and Dart, I took many courses such as UI/UX design and I did a project using the principles I learned and with a team; we are currently developing a mobile app using flutter and I have taken part in many robotics competitions, not to mention my love for reading books. All of this shaped me into the Yazan I am today, and I am still learning from the surrounding people every day, which will hopefully help me become a better person and pursue my dreams.

Let's connect yazansharawi25@gmail.com

Experience

PwC IT Digital Services December 2023 - Present (5 months)

Onex

1 year 3 months

Amman, Jordan

Software Engineer February 2023 - December 2023 (11 months) Amman, Jordan

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and implement robust software systems.
- Led multiple end-to-end projects, from identifying challenges and designing effective solutions to overseeing the seamless implementation of features.
- Using the power of Vue.js and Node.js, we created high-quality, efficient, and scalable backend and frontend components.
- Actively participated in contributing to system optimizations and troubleshooting issues to ensure smooth operation and exceptional user experiences.
- Turning business requirements into a functional application with a good user experience.
- Played a pivotal role in translating complex problems into actionable plans, ensuring the successful delivery of features that significantly contributed to the team's capabilities and project outcomes.

Software Engineer October 2022 - January 2023 (4 months)

Bright engineers

Technical Mentor

September 2019 - October 2022 (3 years 2 months)

Amman, Jordan

- Instructed kids aged 9 to 16 in Lego EV3 Mindstorm technology
- Taught kids about building and programming robots from scratch using problem-solving and teamwork techniques
- Contributed to creating a positive learning environment where young kids could explore engineering and robotics

Jerusalem Insurance Company - شركة القدس للتأمين Intern

September 2021 - September 2021 (1 month)

Amman, Jordan

- Worked on the project called 'Digital Transmission' which aimed to turn all paper works into digital
- Assisted in the development of the company's mobile app
- Gained practical experience in a professional work environment at the largest insurance company in Jordan

Education

Princess Sumaya University for Technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (September 2019 - January 2024)